Guide to the Gerald Stern Papers, 1920s-2012 SC.2007.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Poetry and Other Works, 1940-2012; I.
  - 2015 Addition, 20.
    - Save the Last Dance, 2008
      This subseries contains materials related to Stern's collection of poetry, Save the Last Dance, pubished in 2008 by W.W. Norton and Company. Included are notes and drafts of individual poems, organized alphabetically, followed by typescripts, proofs, and galleys, organized according to the publication process.
      - 59 N. Sitgreaves (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Asphodel (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Bill Matthews (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Cooper Union (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Death by Wind (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Diogenes (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Dream III (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Flute II (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - Glut (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Jackknife (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - He Again (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - His Name (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Lorca (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - Love (Box 45, Folder 14)
      - Love Box (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - My Dear (Box 45, Folder 16)
      - One Day (Box 45, Folder 17)
      - Rapture Lost (Box 45, Folder 18)
      - Rukeyser (Box 45, Folder 19)
      - Save the Last Dance for Me (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - Stomachs (Box 45, Folder 21)
      - Traveling Backward (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - The Truth (Box 45, Folder 23)
      - Unidentified Poem (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - Wordsworth (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - Research for "The Preacher", 2007 (Box 45, Folder 26)
      - Notebook of Rough Drafts and Notes (Box 45, Folder 27-29)
      - Photocopies of pages from notebooks of rough drafts with notes (Box 45, Folder 30)
      - Second and Third Drafts (Box 45, Folder 31)
      - Norton Copyedited Manuscript, 2007 (Box 45, Folder 32)
      - Typescript with Edits (Box 45, Folder 33)
      - Front Matter (Box 45, Folder 34)
      - Norton Page Proof, 1st Pass, 2007 (Box 45, Folder 35)
      - Norton Page Proof, 2nd Pass, 2007 (Box 45, Folder 36)
      - Galley (Box 45, Folder 37)
      - Correspondence, Reviews, and Publication Information, 2007-2009 (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - What I Can't Bear Losing, 2009
      What I Cant' Bear Losing was originally published in 2003. This subseries contains materials related to the 2009 edition which included seven new essays. The subseries includes drafts of new essays, research notes, notebooks, and typescripts, proofs, and drafts.
      - Against Whistling, various drafts with edits (Box 45, Folder 39)
      - Burning Money, research (Box 45, Folder 40)
      - Burning Money, drafts and notebook, 2008 (Box 45, Folder 41)
      - A Guest at the World's Table (Box 45, Folder 42)
      - A Guest at the World's Table, submitted as My Father for the anthology, Growing Up Jewish, 2004 (Box 45, Folder 43)
      - Mother's Day, various drafts with edits (Box 45, Folder 44)
      - Music with Barbara Ras's edits, 2008 (Box 45, Folder 45)
      - Nostalgia, research for rewrite that did not happen, 2008 (Box 45, Folder 46)
      - Plain Talk (Box 45, Folder 47)
      - Ruth, various drafts with edits (Box 45, Folder 48)
      - William Carlos Williams, notebook and various drafts, 2007 (Box 45, Folder 49)
      - Research (Box 45, Folder 50)
      - Old essays, reworked (Box 45, Folder 51)
      - Composition book and small notebook (Box 45, Folder 52)
      - Photocopy of contents of notebook (Box 45, Folder 53)
      - Drafts of Essays, edited by Barbara Ras and correspondence with Ras, 2008 (Box 45, Folder 54)
      - Copyedited penultimate drafts (Box 45, Folder 55)
      - Drafts of introduction (Box 45, Folder 56)
      - Rejected essays, 2009 (Box 45, Folder 57)
      - Copyedited manuscript (Box 45, Folder 58-59)
      - Correspondence regarding book design, 2009 (Box 45, Folder 60)
    - Early Collected Poems, 2010
      Early Collected Poems is a collection of Stern's first six books of poetry, including: Rejoicings, Lucky Life, The Red Coal, Paradise Poems, Lovesick, and Bread Without Sugar. The subseries mostly includes foul matter from Norton.
      - Master with foul matter, 2009 (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
      - First pass with foul matter from Norton, 2009 (Box 46, Folder 4-5)
      - First pass with Stern's changes, 2009 (Box 46, Folder 6-7)
      - Second pass with foul matter from Norton, 2009 (Box 46, Folder 8-9)
      - Second pass with Stern's changes (Box 46, Folder 10-11)
      - Significant changes made to poems by Stern, 2009 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Author's questionnaire for marketing and author memo to production, 2009 (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - Third pass with foul matter from Norton, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 14-15)
      - Third pass with Stern's changes (Box 46, Folder 16)
      - Fourth pass, including only front matter and index, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 17)
      - Fifth pass including only front matter and index, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 18)
      - Copyedited manuscript, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 19)
      - Notes concerning index, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 20)
      - Portion of index, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Stealing History, 2012
      This section inlcudes materials related to Stern's collection of essays,Stealing History, published in 2009 by Trinity University Press and mostly contains Stern's research which consists of printouts of Wikipedia articles, organized alphabetically. Only those Wikipedia articles marked with Stern's notes were retained. For unmaked articles, a list was created and included in the series. The series also includes notes and various drafts of sections and full manuscripts, organized according to the publishing process.
      Note that there is a notebook for In Beauty Bright that contains drafts for Stealing History, located in following subseries.
      - Arshile Gorky (Box 46, Folder 22)
      - Bialystoker (Box 46, Folder 23)
      - Bosnian War (Box 46, Folder 24)
      - Caravaggio (Box 46, Folder 25)
      - Christianity (Box 46, Folder 26)
      - Haiti (Box 46, Folder 27)
      - Hijackers (Box 46, Folder 28)
      - History of Jews in Poland (Box 46, Folder 29)
      - Humor (Box 46, Folder 30)
      - Israel (Box 46, Folder 31)
      - James Schuyler (Box 46, Folder 32)
      - Judaism (Box 46, Folder 33)
      - Lucille Clifton (Box 46, Folder 34)
      - Martin Niemoller (Box 46, Folder 35)
      - Meister Eckhart (Box 46, Folder 36)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 37)
      - Quilts of Gees Bend (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Rwandan Genocide (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Stanley McChrystal (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Travel (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Ukraine (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - War in Darfur (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - The Zone, drafts and research (not published) (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - List of printed Wikipedia and newspaper articles that did not contain Stern's notes (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - Loose drafts (Box 47, Folder 9-10)
      - Notebook of drafts and loose notes (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Notebooks of rough drafts (Box 47, Folder 12-15)
      - Notes (Box 47, Folder 16)
      - Permissions, 2011 (Box 47, Folder 17)
      - Complete draft with edits (Box 47, Folder 18-19)
      - Draft of chapter breakdown (Box 47, Folder 20)
      - Draft, final major changes (Box 47, Folder 21-22)
      - Drafts of sections with edits (Box 47, Folder 23-26)
      - Draft version A (Box 47, Folder 27)
      - Draft version B (Box 47, Folder 28)
      - Draft version C (Box 47, Folder 29)
      - Draft version D (Box 47, Folder 30)
      - Last manuscript with Stern's final edits (Box 47, Folder 31-32)
      - Manuscript with Stern's and Barbara Ras' edits (Box 47, Folder 33)
      - Manuscript with Stern's and Barbara Ras' edits (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - Proof with corrections (Box 48, Folder 2-3)
      - Style sheet and word list, 2011 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Trinity University Press foul matter (Box 48, Folder 5-8)
      - Versions of chapter breakdown (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - In Beauty Bright, 2012
      This section includes materials related to In Beauty Bright, published in 2014 by W.W. Norton and Company, and mostly contains drafts and notes. Note that drafts of In Beauty Bright are also located within a notebook of rough drafts for the unpublished poem "I", which follows this subseries.
      - Eleanor, 2007 (Box 48, Folder 10)
      - Handwritten drafts and notes (Box 48, Folder 11-12)
      - Notebook of rough drafts, notes, and drawings. Includes some drafts from Stealing History (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Rejected poems (Box 48, Folder 14)
      - Two Graces, 2009 (Box 48, Folder 15)
      - Revised drafts (Box 48, Folder 16)
      - Copyedited manuscript from Norton with Stern's last changes (Box 48, Folder 17)
      - Front matter (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - I
      This section includes materials related to Stern's unpublished poem "I" and includes research, drafts, and a notebook, which also includes drafts for In Beauty Bright.
      - Research (Box 48, Folder 19)
      - Notebook of rough drafts, including drafts for In Beauty Bright (Box 48, Folder 20)
      - Rough drafts (Box 48, Folder 21)
      - Rough drafts with revisions (Box 48, Folder 22)
- Articles, Essays, Lectures, Workshops and Other Projects, 1980s-1990s; II.
  This series includes materials related to Stern as editor of various anthologies and his column, Notes From a River, feature in the American Poetry Review from 1979-1984. Also incuded are research and drafts of various articles and essays written by Stern and materials pertaining to lectures,talks, workshops, and interviews published in various journals.
  New material was added to this series in 2015 and can be found within each subseries as "2015 Addition."
  - Articles, 1.
    - Jewish Encyclopedia (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Jewish Encyclopedia (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Jewish Encyclopedia (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - American Jewish Poetry (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - American Jewish Poetry (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Essays, 2.
    - Research for Notes from the River (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Drafts of Notes from the River (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Notes from the River, Column 2 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence concerning Notes on the River (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Drafts of Nostalgia (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - East Liberty notes (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Sabbath (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Port Authority (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Some Secrets (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Living in Ruin (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Caves (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Essay on Heaven (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Essay on Music (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Chanty (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Research for essay on Gil Orlovitz (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Miss Pink at Last (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence concerning Orlovitz essay (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Tilting the Universe (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Notebook (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Research material on Mourning (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Research material on Anti-Semitism (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Research material on James Wright (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Research material on Edith Stein (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - 2015 Addition
      This new material consists of additional drafts from Stern's American Poetry Review column, Notes From the River, as well as older essays that were not published in APR. Also included are newer essays published in various journals.
      - Notes from the River, 1979-1987
        - The Bombing, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 23)
        - Caves, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 24)
        - Coming of Age, 1983 (Box 48, Folder 25)
        - Correspondence, notes, and drafts of unpublished essays, 1979-1988 (Box 48, Folder 26)
        - First and second Column the appeared in APR, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 27)
        - Future of Asbury Park, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 28)
        - Grossman's Lament (Box 48, Folder 29)
        - Honeysuckle, 1983 (Box 48, Folder 30)
        - Notebook of rough drafts (Box 48, Folder 31)
        - Polarity (Box 48, Folder 32)
        - The Sabbath, 1984 (Box 48, Folder 33)
        - Some Secrets, originally published in In Praise of What Persists, 1983 (Box 48, Folder 34)
        - Some Thoughts on God's Grandeur (Box 48, Folder 35)
        - Unpublished manuscript that includes essays from Notes From the River (Box 48, Folder 36)
      - Essays, 1985-2013
        - Andy, essay on Andy Warhol (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - Bud Schulberg remembrance for Norton Poetry website, 2009 (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - December Thirtieth (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Essay on Hart Crane's "Eternity," for "The Poem the Changed my Life" in American Poets magazine, 2012 (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - Essay on Jack Gilbert and Richard Hazley (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - Essay on Jean Valentine for American Poets magazine (Box 49, Folder 6)
        - Essay on Muriel Rukeyer for Poetry magazine, 2012 (Box 49, Folder 7)
        - Essay on Muriel Rukeyser's poem, St. Roach, for Field magazine (Box 49, Folder 8)
        - Essay on Peter Feldstein for The Oxford Photography Project (Box 49, Folder 9)
        - Essay on Poet Laureateship (Box 49, Folder 10)
        - Explanation of poem, Dream IV, for Best American Poetry, 2011 (Box 49, Folder 11)
        - Explanation of poem, Places You Wouldn't Believe, for Poetry East (Box 49, Folder 12)
        - Explanation of poem, Stoop, 2010 (Box 49, Folder 13)
        - For Night to Come, version that appeared in 45 Contemporary Poems, with discussion questions and Stern's responses, 1985 (Box 49, Folder 14)
        - Introduction to Aliki Barnstone's, The Collected Poems C.P. Cavafy, 2006 (Box 49, Folder 15)
        - Introduction to E.J. Garcia's Your Bright Hand, 2011 (Box 49, Folder 16)
        - Introduction to Ross Gay's Against Which, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 17)
        - Lucille Clifton tribute, 2010 (Box 49, Folder 18)
        - Marks of Pain, Marks of Love: The Appreciation of Aghios, essay on Peter Feldstein (Box 49, Folder 19)
        - More Major, essay on Roethke's, The Chums, for Field, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 20)
        - The Morosco, with recent edits, originally appeared in Notes from the River (Box 49, Folder 21)
        - Nowhere USA, essay on William Matthew's poem, Morningside Heights, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 22)
        - Phil Levine remembrance, 2012 (Box 49, Folder 23)
        - Poetry Itself, essay on Linda Gregg (Box 49, Folder 24)
        - Portion of the essay Caves, originally titled Leaf (Box 49, Folder 25)
        - The Quarrel, essay on Stephan Dunn's poem, Don't Do That, 2013 (Box 49, Folder 26)
        - Retrospective on Paul Matthews (Box 49, Folder 27)
        - Review of Arthur Vogelsang's, Left Wing of a Bird, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 28)
        - Statement for Seven Habits of Highly Effective Poets (Box 49, Folder 29)
        - Ted Solotaroff remembrance, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 30)
        - A Toy World, introduction to Illana Shmueli's Towards Babel, 2013 (Box 49, Folder 31)
        - Wedding statement for David and Diane, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 32)
  - Lectures, Workshops and Other Projects, 1979-2007; 3.
    - Thoughts for talks (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Poetry selections for readings (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Poems for talks (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Domestic poetry lecture (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Poetry and Subversion notes (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Stern's statements on his poems (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Notes for a talk on writing programs (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Amazon.Com's Millennium Poem Project (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Content in Poetry talk (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Pound and Paradise lecture (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Poetry and Anthropology lecture (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Speech for New York high school students (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Lecture on Justice and Injustice (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Talk on Persona (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Lecture on Healing (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Coleridge Lecture, New School (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Sonnet Class material (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Oxford photography project (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Introduction to Crossing Limits (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Poetry East essay (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Stern film (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Essays on Growing Up, 1949 versus 1987 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Poet's Project in Philadelphia (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Canthara: essays on W. C. Williams (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Essay on class about Matthew Arnold (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Three Rivers - Ten Years (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Paris essay (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Lecture on What Coheres (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Myself and Walt Whitman (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Introduction to Ploughshares (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - A Few words on form (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Stern on Stern (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - A Seer: essay on Baja (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Life Is Not a River (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Essay on For Night to Come (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Nicaragua (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - What Is A Poet? (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Karl Stirner (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Filling the Page (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Roethke (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Linda Gregg (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Lou Asekolf (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Galway Kinnell (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Muriel Rukeyser (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Allen Grossman (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Kathleen Pierce (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Susan Mitchell (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Bob Haas (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Brenda Hillman (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - Stanley Kunitz (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - Hayden Carruth (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - Bob Behr (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - W. S. Mirwin (Box 13, Folder 53)
    - Chris Davis (Box 13, Folder 54)
    - Bill Matthews (Box 13, Folder 55)
    - Liz Stout (Box 13, Folder 56)
    - Li-Young Lee (Box 13, Folder 57)
    - Deborah Digges (Box 13, Folder 58)
    - Stanley Plumley (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - 2015 Addition
      - Pure and Impure Poetry, delivered at the Academy of Americna Poets Forum, 2009 (Box 49, Folder 33)
      - Research for talk, The Anxiety of I, delivered at the Chancellor's Forum, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 34)
      - The X Factor, delivered in the California foothills, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 35)
  - Interviews, 1981-2012; 4.
    This subseries contains photocopies of published interviews, mostly from journals. Many of the files include transcripts of the interviews and drafts with edits made by Stern as well as correspondence with those that interviewed Stern.
    - Affection for the World: A Conversation with Gerald Stern," Penn State News, 2006 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - A Conversation with Gerald Stern, Rattle, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - A Conversation with Gerald Stern, Fourth Genre, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - A Conversation with Gerald Stern,Willow Spring, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 39)
    - Dictionary of Literary Biography, by Chard deNiord, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 40)
    - Explaining, Explaining: A Conversation with Gerald Stern, Boulevard, 1992 (Box 49, Folder 41)
    - Feelings, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 42)
    - Five Questions: An Interview with Gerald Stern, CutBank, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 43)
    - Gerald Stern: A Rebel Poet Speaks about Memory, Propriety, Sonnets, MFA Programs, and Joy, Drexel Online Journal (includes CD of interview), 2003 (Box 49, Folder 44)
    - Gerald Stern Speaking, Akros, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 45)
    - Gerald Stern: Ten Poems and an Interview, American Poetry Review, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 46)
    - A God in the House: Poets Talk About Faith, 2011 (Box 49, Folder 47)
    - Good News, Bad News: An Interview with Gerald Stern, Delicious Imaginations: Conversations with Contemporary Writers, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 48)
    - I Knew Some of Them, But They All Knew Me: Interview with Gerald Stern, Zone 3, 2012 (Box 49, Folder 49)
    - Interview at New England College, interviewed by Li-Young Lee and Chard deNiord, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 50)
    - Interview with Gerald Stern, Iowa Review, 2 editions, 1989, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 51)
    - An Interview with Gerald Stern, South Florida Poetry Review, 1992 (Box 49, Folder 52)
    - An Interview with Gerald Stern, The Writer's Chronicle, 2012 (Box 49, Folder 53)
    - An Interview with Gerald Stern, Yarrow, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 54)
    - The Literary Interview as Public Performance, Culture and Society, 2013 (Box 49, Folder 55)
    - Lucky Life: An Interview with Gerald Stern, Faultline, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 56)
    - Meaning & Memory: Interviews with Fourteen Jewish Poets, 1996-2001 (Box 49, Folder 57)
    - Melanie Greenhouse Interview, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 58)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding interviews, 1996-2004 (Box 49, Folder 59)
    - Number Your Answers: An Interview with Gerald Stern, Writer's Chronicle, 2006 (Box 49, Folder 60)
    - Paradise? An Interview with Gerald Stern," Chicago Literary Review, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 61)
    - The Paris Years: 1949-1950, interview by Juan Felipe Herrera, 2011-2012 (Box 49, Folder 62)
    - Passwords Primeval: 20 American Poets in Their Own Words, 2009-2010 (Box 49, Folder 63)
    - A Poet of the Mind, Poetry East, 1988 (Box 49, Folder 64)
    - The Poetry of Constant Renewal and Celebration, The Missouri Review, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 65)
    - Rumpus Interview with Gerald Stern, 2010 (Box 49, Folder 66)
    - Smith College Interview, 2012 (Box 49, Folder 67)
    - Splendor in the Weeds: An Interview with Gerald Stern, Text and Performance Quarterly, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 68)
    - You Must Ruin Your Life: An Interview with Gerald Stern, Lyric, 2003 (Box 49, Folder 69)
- Drawings, 1950-1990; III.
  This series contains drawings done mostly by Stern from the 1950s through the 1990s. This does not include the drawings that appeared in his 2014 book of drawings, Dancing with Tears in My Eyes.
  - Cartoons and sketches (Box 49, Folder 60)
  - Cartoons and sketches (Box 49, Folder 61)
  - Other art work (Box 49, Folder 62)
  - Printed sketches (Box 49, Folder 63)
  - Artwork by others (Box 49, Folder 64)
- Correspondence, 1950-2007; IV.
  This series consists of correspondence to and from Stern, arranged alphabetically and by type of correspondent (note that Stern designated these "types").
  New material was added to this series in 2015 and is desidated within the applicable subseries as "2015 Addition."
  - Family, 1918-2007; 1.
    - Stern, David, 1979-2005 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Stern, Ida, 1907-1986 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Stern, Ida, 1946-1986 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Stern, Ida, 1918-1994 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Stern, Patricia, 1950-1985 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Stern, Rachel, 1948-2001 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 2015 Addition, 2007-2011
      - Stern, David, 2007-2009 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Stern-Martin, Rachel, 2009-2011 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Extended Family Members, 2010-2011 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Significant Others, 1977-2006; 2.
    - Apatovsky, Patricia, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Bartas-Smith, Nancy, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Beeman, Robin, 1989-1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Buzzetta, Joanne, 1994-1998 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Carmichael, Lorraine, 1988-1994 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Crow, Mary, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Davinoff, Linda, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Finkelstein, Caroline, 1994-1998 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Freund, Diane, 1982-1988 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Freund, Diane, 1989-2006 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Greene, Patty, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Griffith, Pat, 1984-2005 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Henley, Patricia, 1988-2004 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Hurwitz, Ellen, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - "Irena" (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Liebricht, Sauvegnon, 1990-1992 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Macari, Anne Marie (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - MacDougall, Jo, 1990-2004 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - McCormick, Nora, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - McKinney, Irene, 1988-1994 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - "Mavis" (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Mendel, Olga, 1982-1991 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Rago, Juliet (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Rock, Judy, 1977-1989 (Box 14, Folder 30)